Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rayaarul (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Creative Problem Solving
Observation
Business Technology Optimization

Arulappan Antonysamy

A Passionate Full Stack Developer & Technical Lead Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Summary

Seasoned Associate Architect & Technical Lead specializing in .NET Technologies with over 14 years of experience, including international assignments in Hong Kong, Bahrain, and Abu Dhabi. Holds a Master's degree in Computer Applications (MCA) and is adept in a wide array of technical skills including C#.NET, VB.NET, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET MVC Core with EF & EF Core, LINQ, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, SSRS, SSIS, ETL, StreamServe, K2 Blackpearl, React, Angular, Microservices, Azure, DevOps, and SQL Server.

Experience

Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt. Ltd.
Technical Lead
February 2011 - August 2023 (12 years 7 months)
Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Reduced the support cost by 20% after automating Reporting Functions. Reduced the server cost by 100% by enhancing the reporting module catter to crystal reporting automation. Liaised with clients to understand the business requirements. Sharing ideas in technical design to optimize the solution with all the requirements met in an effective manner. Providing the user demos and trainings on the developments done. Addressing PROD issues on priority and enable the BAU Solving and guiding team members technically solving the real pressing time sensitive issues. Involved in most of the System Upgrade, Report Consolidation, Platform Stability, Automation. Involved in end-to-end phases of the SDLC – Software Development Life Cycle. Identifying areas of improvement, chances for automation and delegating to team after laying the foundation.

Indusmedia Tech Pvt. Ltd.
Senior Software Engineer
April 2010 - February 2011 (11 months)
Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Analyzing and architecting complex business functions. Automating and enhancing redundant and laborious processes and functions. Business valuation. Advanced debugging skills. Database Knowledge. Data structure knowledge.

Sunsmart Tech. Pvt. Ltd. Senior Software Engineer October 2009 - February 2010 (5 months) Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Analyzing and architecting complex business functions. Automating and enhancing redundant and laborious processes and functions. Business valuation. Advanced debugging skills. Database Knowledge. Data structure knowledge.

Education

Indira Gandhi National Open University

Master of Computer Applications, Computer Science · (2006 - 2008)

Indira Gandhi National Open University
BCA - Bachelor of Computer Applications · (2006 - 2006)